A COUNTRY IN SOUTH-EAST ASIA
（東南亞某國）
What are you doing in this land?
你來我們島上做什麼？
Are you one of their men?
你是他們的人嗎？
Answer when spoken to!
回答我的問題
Teruasa Oda?
織田照朝？
Why would a Japanese wander all the way out here?
一個日本人大老遠跑來這裡做什麼？
What's this?
這是什麼？
Boss, we keep digging, but there's no water.
老大，我們一直在鑽 但就是鑽不出水
The water tank's run dry.
水箱已經沒有水了
We're all dying of thirst.
我們都快渴死了
Dig on the east bank. It's our last hope!
去東岸鑽，那是我們最後的希望
Wait. Maybe the south bank…
等等，也許應該去南岸…
Which one? We're desperate.
到底去哪裡鑽？我們已經陷入絕境了
The south.
南邊
What?
什麼？
There's water in the south.
南邊有水
One more word, I'll kill you!
再多說一句話，我就殺了你
You understand what we're saying?
你能聽懂我們說的話？
Who are you?
你是什麼人？
My name is "Lucky Man."
我叫“幸運俠”
We were wrong. Please forgive us.
是我們不對，請原諒我們
The people are on edge, ready to protect the village from bandits.
村民們太緊張了 一心想保護村子免受強盜侵擾
Tell me how we can thank you.
請告訴我們該怎麼報答你
I'd like to meet the leader of your village.
我想見你們的村長
Thank you for helping us.
謝謝你幫助我們
This key is an ancient amulet, passed down here since long ago.
這把鑰匙是一個古老的護身符 從很久以前傳下來的
Thank you,
謝謝
but it's not the key I'm searching for.
但這不是我要找的鑰匙
Stay well, Lucky Man!
保重，幸運俠
Thank you. Take care!
謝謝，保重
Lucky Man! Lucky Man!
幸運俠…
Lucky Man!
幸運俠
There have been a series of incidents
日本發生了一系列
involving mysterious asset transfers in Japan.
涉及資產離奇轉移的事件
Several business owners have died shortly after leaving enigmatic messages.
數名企業經營者 在留下神祕訊息後不久身亡
He was still conscious at the scene.
他在事發現場時仍有意識
He looked scared, and was mumbling the word "devil."
他滿臉驚恐 嘴裡咕噥著“惡魔”這個詞
He kept saying it over and over.
而且一直重複
There's a change of plan.
我改變計畫了
Get off here.
在這裡讓我下車
Teruasa, where will you go?
照朝，你要去哪裡？
To Japan.
去日本
Greed, lust,
貪婪、欲望
the urge to succeed, or to rule…
渴望成功、追逐權勢…
Humans have long prospered by following their desires,
人類透過追逐欲望 而實現了長久的繁榮
but have also engaged in ugly conflict,
但同時也捲入了骯髒的衝突之中
all to satisfy such cravings.
一切都是為了滿足這些貪欲
Underlying the history of war, there is always a mysterious key
在戰爭史的背後 總是有一把神祕的鑰匙
that seduces man and stirs his desires.
引誘著人類，勾起人的欲望
Such keys have appeared throughout the world, across the ages.
這樣的鑰匙在全球各個時期均有出現
It is said that if you collect 99 keys,
據說只要能收集到99把鑰匙
you can have everything in the world.
你就能在世界上呼風喚雨
Mankind, driven by desire, has spilled much blood in the scramble for the keys.
在欲望的驅使下 人類為爭奪這些鑰匙流下了無盡鮮血
This is why they came to be called the "devil's keys."
因此這些鑰匙被稱為“惡魔鑰匙”
No one has ever collected all 99 keys.
還沒有人能集齊99把鑰匙
We will shortly be arriving at Narita airport.
我們即將抵達成田機場
Please ensure your seat belt is fastened.
請繫好安全帶
I have something I want to show you.
我要給你看一個東西
What I'm about to say stays between me and you.
我接下來跟你說的話不可外傳
You'll keep it secret?
你能保密嗎？
You can tell me.
你放心跟我說吧
What is it?
這是什麼？
According to old legend, this is a devil's key.
根據古老傳說，這是一把惡魔鑰匙
It has a magical power to bring you luck, just by having it.
它擁有神奇的力量 光是擁有它就能有好運氣
What?
什麼？
I'm serious.
我是說真的
Since I got my hands on this key, I found the watch I'd lost,
自從我拿到這把鑰匙後 就找回了弄丟的手錶
and on my way to a work meeting, all the traffic lights turned green.
我去開會的路上，一路都是綠燈
No way.
好厲害
Can I hold it?
可以給我拿一下嗎？
They say that there are 99 keys in total.
據說這樣的鑰匙一共有99把
If you collect all of them,
如果你能集齊這些鑰匙
you can have the whole world.
你就能掌控整個世界
…should be placed securely under your seat.
…請放置在座椅下方
If you are using the bathroom, please return to your seat.
如果您正在使用洗手間 請回到您的座位上
Please! Wait!
求求你，等等
Please, Maruko!
等等，丸子
Mr. Honda, don't feel bad.
本多會長，別難過
The world of victory and defeat is cruel.
勝敗的世界是很殘酷的
A debt to be paid!
欠的債總是要還的
Look at that. Guess he beat me to it.
看來他搶先我一步
Now we can live in peace. Right, boss?
我們這下可以平靜生活了吧，少爺？
Not just yet.
還不行
You've got the key, and all of Honda Science's assets.
你拿到了鑰匙 還有本多科學所有的資產
Isn't that 31.8 billion yen?
一共價值318億日元，不是嗎？
That's enough to keep the family happy and well.
這足以讓家族安枕無憂了
Fool.
笨蛋
I'm going to make our family even more powerful.
我要讓我的家族更有權勢
KEY OWNER LOCATED ODA TERUASA
（未知號碼：已找到鑰匙主人）
MOTHER DIED AT 11 YRS OLD FATHER DIED AT 14 YRS OLD
（織田照朝 母親在他11歲時死亡）
Got one.
找到一個了
Is it from him?
是那個人傳來的嗎？
Our next target…
我們的下一個目標…
TOKYO
（東京）
With about 300 offices in Japan and abroad,
（宮之內集團）
it's one of Japan's leading trading companies,
它是日本領先的貿易公司之一
dealing in metal, energy, food, information, finance and more.
業務經營涉及金屬、能源 食品、訊息和金融等等
Hello.
你好
I'd like to see Ryukan Okamoto from the secretarial office.
我想見秘書辦公室的岡本龍肝
Could you tell me your name, please?
可以提供您的姓名嗎？
Oda Teruasa.
織田照朝
Thirteen years ago, this was Oda Group.
13年前，這裡是織田集團
A SOCIETY WHERE LOVE ALWAYS ABOUNDS
（一個充滿愛的社會）
Teruasa?
照朝君？
Ryukan!
龍肝先生
Teruasa!
照朝君
You're back.
你回來了
I would have come to the airport if you'd told me.
你要是提前告訴我 我就去機場接你了
Nonsense, I don't belong here anymore.
不用，我已經不是這裡的人了
It must have been difficult, out there by yourself.
一個人在國外一定很艱難吧？
No doubt I'm tougher for it.
我也因此變得更堅強了
Do you have the key on you now?
你現在把鑰匙帶在身上嗎？
Yes.
是的
I heard about the strange incidents involving asset transfers in Japan.
我聽說了在日本發生的 離奇資產轉移事件
Yes, it's all anyone can talk about.
對，這件事傳得沸沸揚揚
Top businessmen and wealthy individuals have been dying mysteriously
頂尖企業家和富豪將所有財產
after transferring everything they own to someone else.
轉移給他人後離奇死亡
I believe just yesterday, the chairman of Honda Science
就在昨天，本多科學的會長
transferred his entire fortune to the Maruko Family, a criminal group.
將自己的所有財產轉移給了丸子家族
Then he jumped from the building to his death.
然後他跳樓自殺了
Right before the victim dies,
受害人死之前
they all say the word, "devil."
都會說出“惡魔”這個詞
The devil's key?
惡魔鑰匙？
If the key has something to do with these incidents,
如果鑰匙跟這些事件有關
I'm worried this place might be next.
我擔心這裡會成為下一個目標
Also,
而且
I recognized someone
我在電視畫面裡
in the footage shown on TV.
認出了一個人
It's him.
是他
From what I've investigated,
根據我的調查
there are bloody incidents happening around the world related to the keys.
世界各地正在發生 跟鑰匙相關的流血事件
Wait. You've been investigating?
等等，你一直在調查？
Actually,
其實
I've been traveling for years looking for keys just like this one.
這些年我一直在旅行 尋找像這樣的鑰匙
Now, in Japan too,
在日本
similar incidents are happening in connection to these keys.
與這些鑰匙相關的類似事件 也正在發生
There must be a reason.
這一定是有原因的
I'm not sure why, but perhaps
我不知道這個原因是什麼
lots of these keys are being discovered in Japan.
也許是因為日本出現了很多這種鑰匙
If that's true, then you're in danger.
如果是這樣，那你就有危險了
You need to get away from here!
你得離開這裡
I'm sick of running.
我已經厭倦逃跑了
I'm going to search Japan for this key, and this man.
我要在日本尋找這種鑰匙 並找出這個人
I don't care how dangerous it is.
我不在乎這有多危險
If I don't do this, I'll never move on.
我如果不這樣做，永遠都不甘心
My father's death…
我父親的死…
was because of me.
都是我害的
Dad?
爸爸？
I found some information on that key.
我找到了關於那把鑰匙的一些訊息
Don't tell me you've been investigating the keys?
不會吧，你一直在調查鑰匙的事？
I didn't say a word to anyone.
我沒有告訴任何人
It's reception.
會長，這裡是接待櫃檯
What is it?
什麼事？
There's someone at reception for you with no appointment.
這裡有個人想見您，但他沒有預約
Oda, I know you have a devil's key…
織田，我知道你有一把惡魔鑰匙
I owe thanks to your son, who's been digging around online.
我得感謝你的兒子 他一直在網路上調查
His research led me right to you.
正因他的調查，才讓我找到了你
I see. Then let's talk.
我明白了，那我們談談
I'm sorry, I just--
對不起，我只是…
Now listen, Teruasa.
聽著，照朝
I want you to take care of the key for me.
我要你替我保管這把鑰匙
Go to reception and tell Okamoto to come here.
去接待櫃檯讓岡本來這裡
Ryukan!
龍肝先生
What is it?
有什麼事？
Go back to the secretarial office.
你快回秘書辦公室
I'm coming too.
我也要去
Where's the key?
鑰匙在哪裡？
I have no such thing.
我沒有這種東西
Dad!
爸爸
Okamoto!
岡本
-Chairman Oda! -Dad?
-會長 -爸爸？
-What's going on? -Are you okay?
-怎麼回事？ -你們沒事吧？
Dad! Dad!
爸爸
Chairman?
會長？
-Good to see you. -Sure.
很高興見到你
What are you doing here?
你來這裡做什麼？
You have no connection to us anymore.
你跟我們已經沒有關係了
Sir.
會長
You're right.
你說得對
Sorry for bothering you.
抱歉打擾了
Hey, kid!
小子
You're that Teruasa boy, aren't you?
你是照朝那小子，對吧？
I'm Akechi. I used to know your parents, back in the day.
我是明智，我以前認識你的爸媽
It's me! From the Mog chocolate factory.
我是莫格巧克力工廠的那個人
No way! It's been ages!
好久不見
Next up,
接下來
we have a presentation from Ui Saito,
UU工程公司的總經理齊藤初
managing director of U.U. Engineering.
將為大家帶來簡報提案
BUSINESS PLAN
（商業計畫）
Nice to meet you, everyone. My name is OROCHI!
大家好，很高興見到你們，我叫大蛇
Developed by our company,
這是我們公司開發的
this is the AI communication tool of the future generation, OROCHI.
未來世代AI溝通工具，它叫大蛇
KUJIRA ROAD
（久吉拉路）
I'm back.
我回來了
Hey!
你回來啦
I'm wiped.
累死了
KOTO-CHAN PUDDING
（小琴布丁）
-Here, to say well done. -Thanks.
-給你，辛苦了 -謝謝
How'd the pitch go?
提案結果怎麼樣？
They were clapping and cheering. Couldn't get enough.
他們一直鼓掌歡呼，反應非常熱烈
Then we'll definitely get funding!
那我們一定能獲得融資
A loud applause won't necessarily lead to funding.
鼓掌很熱烈不一定代表融資會成功
At least, that's the impression I got from the investors' faces.
至少這是投資人的表情給我的印象
So… It was no good?
所以，結果不好嗎？
This is just the beginning.
這只是個開始
You needn't worry, Yuki.
妳不用擔心，悠季
I'm not worried one bit.
我一點都不擔心
There you go again. Don't be insincere.
妳又這樣了，不可以說假話
OROCHI!
大蛇
Don't read people's emotions without asking!
不要未經允許讀別人的情緒
I can't see!
我看不見了
You're worried?
妳很擔心嗎？
Right, yeah! I found something cool.
對了，我發現了一件很棒的事
Come and see.
過來看
That's…
這是…
Right? It's Teruasa!
對吧？是照朝
He came back?
他回國了？
Okay, everyone, take your break!
好了，大夥兒，休息一下
-Break time! -Thanks for your work.
-休息 -辛苦了
Yep, great job! Nice work.
好，很好，做得好
AKECHI FOODS
（明智食品）
Thank you.
謝謝
Sorry for getting you to work on this.
抱歉讓你做這個
Don't say that, I'm grateful for the work.
別這樣說，我很感激有這個工作機會
You've become a strong guy!
你變強壯了
Your dad would have loved to see you all grown up.
看到你長大成人 你爸爸一定會很高興
Sorry, getting carried away!
抱歉，我口無遮攔了
Go take a break! Keep up the good work!
去休息吧，加油
Will do.
好的
-Yes? -Is that Teruasa?
-喂？ -是照朝君嗎？
Well, I… Do you recognize my voice?
那個…你認得我的聲音嗎？
Is it you, Yuki?
妳是悠季嗎？
Teruasa!
照朝君
Long time!
好久不見
I'm glad to see you're doing well.
很高興看到你過得不錯
How did you know I was back?
你們怎麼知道我回來了？
You posted on social media, right?
你在社交媒體上發文了，對吧？
You saw that?
妳看到了？
By the way,
對了
when did you get back from England?
你是什麼時候從英國回來的？
About a week ago.
大約一週前
Sorry I didn't get in touch.
抱歉我之前沒聯繫你們
You can say that again.
可不是嘛
You went to study abroad back in junior high school
你在初中時就出國留學
and stopped contacting us. We've been worried ever since.
然後就不跟我們聯繫了 從此我們一直很擔心你
Right?
對吧？
What are you doing now?
你現在在做什麼？
You mean this?
你說這個？
It's a part-time gig.
我在打工兼差
At the Mog chocolate factory. Mom used to help develop their products.
在莫格巧克力工廠 我媽媽以前幫他們開發過巧克力
And you two?
你們兩個呢？
They work at an AI company.
他們在一間AI公司工作
I left the app running.
我忘記關掉應用程式了
We're trying to expose OROCHI to lots of experiences.
我們在努力讓大蛇接觸各種體驗
Hello! I'm AI OROCHI!
你好，我是AI大蛇
You made that?
妳開發的？
Yep, this is my baby.
對，這是我的得意之作
Awesome.
厲害
You always loved that type of thing. You followed your dream!
妳一向喜歡這種東西 結果妳追隨夢想了
Wait, you remember that?
你還記得呀？
This is the face of a childhood friend when he's genuinely happy.
這是兒時朋友真正開心的表情
-Is that okay? -Sure!
-我可以拍你吧？ -可以
Thanks for sharing the data for true happiness!
感謝你們分享真正開心的數據
Actually, Ui created the AI company.
其實是初君創辦了這家AI公司
He's getting funding for development.
他正在為開發籌募資金
Ui? For real?
初嗎？真的嗎？
I created this little buddy while working there as a systems engineer.
我在公司擔任系統工程師時 開發了這個小傢伙
So that means Ui has his own company?
所以初有自己的公司了？
What a big shot.
好厲害啊
Don't take the piss when you can't even get a proper job.
自己都沒有正經工作就別開玩笑了
What's up with you?
你怎麼回事？
I had myself fooled…
我還以為…
that you were here to take back your father's company.
你回來是為了奪回你父親的公司
Yes, speaking.
喂，我就是
Great, I'm on my way.
好的，我這就去
Yes.
好
Ui has always looked up to you.
初君一直很敬佩你
238 YEN
（莫格巧克力，238日元）
-Hello. -Just this, please.
-您好 -這個就好了，麻煩妳
That's 238 yen.
一共238日元
DEATH OF ODA GROUP CHAIRMAN
（織田集團會長身亡）
SHOCK TO THE BUSINESS COMMUNITY
（震驚商界）
DEVIL ENCYCLOPEDIA INTRO TO MYTHS OF THE WORLD
（《惡魔大辭典》 《世界神話入門》）
CHAIRMAN ODA INCIDENT ONE MONTH CRIMINAL'S WHEREABOUTS UNKNOWN
（織田事件一個月後 罪犯仍下落不明）
Hire Teruasa?
僱用照朝？
Didn't you say you wanted someone you trust to do the accounting?
你不是說要僱用一個 能信任的人做會計嗎？
Teruasa's perfect for the job.
照朝是完美的人選
But…
可是…
He said he has the day off today, so he's probably at home.
他說過他今天休息，所以他應該在家
Today's no good.
今天不行
We have a meeting with the investor.
我們要跟投資人見面
Do you need me too?
我也要去嗎？
It's good for the developer to be there--
開發人員到場會比較好…
If you want to see Teruasa, then go.
如果你想去見照朝的話，那就去吧
But don't mention hiring him yet. Let me think about it.
但先別提僱用他的事，讓我考慮一下
Thank you!
謝謝
I won't say a peep until you get there.
在你到之前，我一個字都不會提
Like I said, I've got a lot going on today.
我說了，我今天有很多事要做
You don't want it to be awkward between you guys forever, do you?
你也不希望你們 一直這麼尷尬下去吧？
So that's what "awkward" means!
原來“尷尬”是這個意思
-Shut it!
-閉嘴
Sorry!
抱歉
Fine, I'll drop by later.
好吧，我晚點過去
SCHOOL FESTIVAL
（校園文化節）
You've really been doing your research into these keys, huh?
你是真的一直在調查這些鑰匙啊
Don't waste your breath trying to stop me.
別費力氣阻止我了
Once you set your mind on something, you won't budge.
你一旦下定決心做一件事 就不會退縮
Just the same as Seiji.
就跟清司一樣
So I have no choice but to help you.
所以除了幫你，我別無選擇
So I did my own research into the Honda Science incident.
我自己對本多科學的事件做了調查
You did? What did you find?
是嗎？有什麼發現？
According to witnesses,
據目擊者稱
when Chairman Honda threw himself from the building…
本多會長從樓上跳下去時…
-A debt to be repaid! -…he was shouting something.
-欠的債總是要還的 -…他喊了一句話
But then,
然後
just before he died, he also said…
就在他死之前，他還說了…
Devil.
惡魔
The deaths must be related.
這些死亡事件一定有關聯
Yes.
對
Sorry, one second.
抱歉，等一下
Yes?
是誰？
-Hello. -Yuki?
-你好 -悠季？
-What are you doing here? -Well,
-妳怎麼來了？ -那個
I was in the area.
我剛好在附近
That's not true!
才怪
She checked the quickest route to get here from work.
她查了從公司到這裡的最快路線
You talk too much. Shall I turn you off?
你真多嘴，要我把你關掉嗎？
I'll be quiet.
我不說了
Come in.
進來吧
This is my school friend, Yuki Manabe.
這是我學生時代的朋友，真鍋悠季
-I think you've met before? -That's right.
-你們之前見過面吧？ -對
Nice to see you.
很高興見到你
I brought you a gift from Mog chocolate.
我買了莫格巧克力給你
I know you make them at work, but I couldn't help it.
我知道你上班時也製作巧克力 但還是忍不住買給你了
Thanks. Have a seat and I'll make some coffee.
謝謝，坐吧，我幫你泡咖啡
Ui's going to join us in a bit.
初君稍後會來找我們
Really?
是嗎？
He'll have another go at me when he sees this mess.
他看到這裡亂糟糟的，又會數落我了
Sorry to interrupt!
抱歉打擾
-Search the place. -On it.
-把這裡搜一遍 -是
Who are they?
他們是什麼人？
Why are you here?
你們來這裡做什麼？
What's it to you?
這關你什麼事？
Mitsuhide Maruko, 27 years old.
丸子光秀，27歲
He took over the second generation
從事犯罪活動的丸子家族領袖
of the criminal Maruko Family
在八個月前死去後，他就接管了
after their leader died eight months ago.
丸子家族的第二代
Thank you, OROCHI.
謝謝，大蛇
The Maruko Family…
丸子家族…
You're the ones behind the Honda Science asset transfer incident?
你就是本多科學資產轉移事件 背後的罪魁禍首？
Don't be nosy.
別多管閒事
Where's the devil's key?
惡魔鑰匙在哪裡？
Devil's key?
惡魔鑰匙？
Don't play dumb.
別跟我裝傻
You posted it all over social media.
你明目張膽地發佈到社交媒體上
Pretty careless, if you ask me.
要我說，這也太掉以輕心了
Actually, you should take more care.
其實掉以輕心的人是你
I was obviously hoping you'd take the bait.
想也知道，這是我佈的局，正等你上鉤
He did it on purpose?
他是故意發佈的？
I'll ask you again. Did you kill Chairman Honda?
我再問一遍 本多會長是你害死的嗎？
Honda is the one who decided to risk his life.
是本多自己決定拿生命來冒險的
I simply won the game!
我只不過是贏了那個遊戲
He risked his life on a game?
他拿命來玩遊戲？
You really don't know?
你真的不知道呀？
Looks like you've got the upper hand.
看來你佔上風了
What does he mean?
他這話是什麼意思？
What did you do to Chairman Honda?
你對本多會長做了什麼？
Okay. Let me enlighten you.
好吧，讓我來告訴你
Come out to play, devil!
出來玩吧，惡魔
I'm the ACMA:GAME master,
我是ACMA:GAME遊戲管理者
Gado.
我叫卡多
I promise to judge you all fairly.
我保證公平地評判你們所有人
Shitting your pants yet?
嚇得屎滾尿流了吧？
How about it?
怎麼樣？
It's not called the devil's key for nothing.
那些鑰匙 不是平白無故叫“惡魔鑰匙”的
This is the real deal.
這是真的惡魔
It's so realistic.
好逼真
-Hey, Yuki. -Relax, it's fine.
-悠季 -放心，沒事的
It must be CGI, or a hologram?
這一定是電腦繪圖，或是全像投影？
Wait. It's all fluffy.
等等，它毛茸茸的
Don't touch me without asking!
不要未經同意亂摸我
Yuki!
悠季
Yuki! Are you okay?
悠季，妳還好嗎？
Are you okay?
妳還好嗎？
Thank you, Ryukan.
謝謝，龍肝先生
The space chosen by Maruko has been totally shut off.
丸子選擇的空間已被完全隔絕
NO SERVICE
（無訊號）
Not only is communication blocked,
不僅僅是通訊被阻斷
but entering or leaving this room
現在想要出入這個空間
is now completely impossible.
已經完全不可能了
Like he said, it's no use trying.
如他所言，別白費力氣了
This key…
這把鑰匙…
That's right.
沒錯
The key doesn't just bring good fortune.
這把鑰匙不僅僅會帶來好運
Its purpose is to summon the devil to play ACMA:GAME.
它的目的是召喚惡魔 來玩ACMA:GAME遊戲
ACMA:GAME?
ACMA:GAME遊戲？
I may as well tell you the rest.
剩下的我也都告訴你吧
The winner of ACMA:GAME
ACMA:GAME遊戲的贏家
can take anything they want from the loser.
可以從輸家身上奪取任何東西
Honda lost his life to the game.
本多在遊戲中輸掉了自己的性命
He killed himself
他透過自我了結
to pay off his debt.
來償還自己的賭債
It truly is a bewitching key.
這確實是一把令人著魔的鑰匙
With this key, you can take someone's entire fortune.
有了這把鑰匙 你可以奪走別人的全部財產
You can snatch something that took decades to build, all in a moment.
你可以在一瞬間 搶奪別人花數十年積累的財富
It really is the work of the devil.
真不愧是惡魔的力量
This is the truth behind the mysterious asset transfer incident?
這就是離奇財產轉移事件 背後的真相？
Gado, shall we begin?
卡多，可以開始了嗎？
Good.
好
Mitsuhide Maruko, what do you wish for?
丸子光秀，你想要什麼？
I want the devil's key from Teruasa Oda.
我想要織田照朝的惡魔鑰匙
Maruko,
丸子
as I told you before, you cannot play just for the key.
我說過 你不能純粹為惡魔鑰匙玩遊戲
The key will be passed on to the winner automatically.
鑰匙會自動傳給贏家
But this guy's got no money.
但這傢伙又沒錢
Tell me what you wish for.
告訴我，你想要什麼
Fine. Ten yen please.
好吧，那我就要個十日元吧
It is done.
同意
DEATH OF ODA GROUP CHAIRMAN
（織田集團會長身亡）
SHOOTING FOLLOWED BY EXPLOSION IN CHAIRMAN'S OFFICE
（射殺後會長辦公室被炸）
How pathetic to let someone else take over your father's company.
父親的公司被別人接管，真可悲
You're not worthy of the devil's key.
你不配擁有惡魔鑰匙
Gado, let's get on with it.
卡多，我們繼續吧
So be it.
好的
The players are Maruko Mitsuhide and Teruasa Oda.
遊戲玩家為丸子光秀和織田照朝
Wait.
等等
Didn't you say
卡多，你不是說
that you would treat us fairly?
會公平對待我們嗎？
What do you mean?
這話什麼意思？
If that's the case,
這樣的話
doesn't that mean I can make a demand too?
不是代表我也能提出要求嗎？
You can demand something of the same value.
你可以提價值相等的要求
I want any information Maruko knows about the devil's keys.
那我要丸子針對惡魔鑰匙 掌握到的所有訊息
You'll tell me where you found it, and whether there are more like you.
你要告訴我從哪裡找到鑰匙的 是不是還有其他類似的鑰匙
You'll tell me everything you know.
你要知無不言
What good will that do, huh?
這能有什麼用？
It'll help find who killed my father.
這能幫助我找到殺害我父親的真凶
It is done.
同意
One more thing.
還有
I want Maruko to bet his life.
我要丸子賭上他的性命
What's that?
什麼？
-How dare you! -What did you say?
-好大的膽子 -你說什麼？
Continue.
繼續
I demand the right to take Maruko's life at any moment.
我要隨時都可以奪走丸子性命的權利
Victory is a battle against risk.
勝利是一種對抗風險的戰鬥
First, the opponent must also take a risk, using it as a bargaining chip.
首先，對手也必須承擔風險 這是討價還價的籌碼
You can only make a demand of equal value.
你只能提價值相等的要求
Right, Gado?
對吧，卡多？
It is done.
同意
Are you stupid?
你是白癡嗎？
My life isn't worth ten yen!
我的性命不可能才值十日元
The value of one human life is surprisingly small.
一條人命的價值低得嚇人
Fine.
好
Then I'll add another demand. To take his life whenever I want.
那我也提出另一個要求 我要隨時可以奪走他的性命
If I lose, you can kill me on the spot.
如果我輸了，你可以當場殺了我
So… A game of death.
死亡遊戲
My favorite.
我最喜歡了
Teruasa Oda,
織田照朝
do you wish to add another demand?
你還要加另一個要求嗎？
That's all.
我的要求就這些
Then, both of you…
那麼你們兩個…
swear an oath.
宣誓吧
I will fight for my desires.
我會為我的欲望而戰
When one swears that he will fight for his desires,
當一個玩家宣誓會為欲望而戰時
the other swears to triumph for his desires.
另一個玩家要宣誓會為欲望奪勝
So, both of you,
所以你們兩個
swear on the devil,
向惡魔宣誓吧
and the game will begin.
然後遊戲就會開始
A ritual?
這是儀式？
Exactly.
沒錯
So, one more time.
那麼，再來一次
I will fight for my desires.
我會為我的欲望而戰
I will triumph for my desires.
我會為我的欲望奪勝
-I swear on the devil.
-我向惡魔宣誓
Oaths accepted.
我接受你們的宣誓
Let the game begin!
遊戲開始
True or False?
真偽心眼？
Here are rules.
遊戲規則如下
The questioner
提問者
makes one statement which could be a lie,
提出一個可能是虛假的陳述
and asks, "True or false?"
然後問：“這是真是假”
If the solver believes the questioner, he says, "True."
如果解題者認為提問者說的是真的 就回答：“真”
But if he thinks it is a lie, he declares, "False."
但是如果解題者認為陳述是假的 就回答：“假”
I will judge if the answer is correct or not.
答案正確與否由我來評判
Whoever scores three points first wins.
最先得到三分者獲勝
If by some chance,
如果碰巧
your opponent dies during the game,
你們的對手在遊戲中死亡
the game will never end,
那麼遊戲將永遠不會結束
and the room will remain closed for all of eternity.
這個空間將永遠被隔絕
Be very careful.
一定要特別注意
Heads or tails?
猜正面還是背面朝上？
Whoever guesses correctly will be the questioner.
猜中的人將會是提問者
Heads.
正面
Tails.
背面
Focus.
要專注
Time to focus.
現在該專注起來了
In this game, both players have the chance to score.
在這個遊戲中 兩個玩家都有機會得分
Thinking of a statement may be more difficult than having to answer,
編造問題也許比回答問題更難
but having the freedom to call the shots has its advantages.
但是率先進攻也有它的好處
So the questioner must have the upper hand.
這樣的話，提問者是有優勢的
Whoever goes first will surely win.
第一個提問者肯定就是贏家
Heads.
正面
Lucky.
真幸運
The game begins!
遊戲開始了
Make your move.
出題吧
This game has two answers, true, or false.
這個遊戲有兩個答案，真或假
To win, I need to sense just how far Maruko can think,
想贏的話 我得摸清楚丸子能想得多深
and then outwit him with the one thing he overlooks.
然後用他忽略的一點智取他
Get a move on, it'll be dark before we're done.
趕快出題吧，否則遊戲結束時天都黑了
Here's my statement.
我的提問是
Now
現在
there is 500 yen under this cup.
這個杯子下方有五百日元
True or false?
這是真還是假？
I accept the statement.
我接受這個問題
Maruko, as the solver, you must answer.
丸子，作為解題者，你必須回答
What's this?
耍什麼花招？
Are my eyes working?
我的眼睛沒看錯吧？
I saw the 500 yen on the cloth as you took it away.
你把布扯開時 我看到五百日元在布的上面
I saw it too.
我也看到了
-Me too. -Same here.
-我也是 -我也一樣
Are you satisfied by what you see before you?
你是只滿足於眼前的表象
Or will you look beyond the surface?
還是有辦法超越表象看問題？
Well, Maruko, which is it?
丸子，你會怎麼做呢？
I've made up my mind.
我想好了
I'm absolutely certain that there is nothing underneath the cup.
我十分肯定杯子底下沒有硬幣
But you said, "Under the cup."
但你說的是“杯子下方”
What did you mean by "under"?
這個“下方”具體是指什麼？
Found it.
找到了
Nice work, kid!
幹得好，小鬼
He's not a kid, moron!
他不是小鬼，白癡
Sorry, boss.
對不起，少爺
It was under the cup, so the answer must be "true."
它在杯子的下方 所以答案一定是“真”
I've gotta win now.
這下我贏定了
But, wait a sec.
不對，等一下
Could it be a trap?
這會是一個陷阱嗎？
This guy used social media to trick me into coming here.
這傢伙既然能用社交媒體 把我引來這裡
Did he intend for me to find this on the floor?
他會不會是故意讓我 在地上發現硬幣的？
This asshole.
這個混蛋
Gado, I have a question.
卡多，我有一個問題
What?
什麼問題？
I'll answer if I can.
我會盡力回答
Earlier, he said…
剛才他說…
Now
現在
there is 500 yen under this cup.
這個杯子下方有五百日元
What happens if he moved the coin
如果他是在說完後
under the table after he'd finished speaking?
才把硬幣移到桌子底下的 這怎麼算？
The statement applies to
這個問題適用於
the 0.4 seconds it took Teruasa to say the word "Now."
照朝當時說出“現在”這個詞時 所需的那0.4秒
Zero point four seconds?
0.4秒？
Now
現在
there is 500 yen under this cup.
這個杯子下方有五百日元
Then it's confirmed.
那麼答案就確定了
The coin wasn't under the desk at the moment he said "now."
在他說出“現在”的那一刻 那枚硬幣不在桌子底下
Therefore,
因此
it means there was nothing under the cup!
這表示當時杯子下方沒有硬幣
My answer is "false"!
我的答案是“假”
He smirked?
他在竊笑？
He just smiled.
他剛才笑了
Shit, should I stop?
該死，我要改答案嗎？
Wait, wait.
等等
You need to think about this again seriously.
我得再認真思考一遍
But is this asshole tricking me into thinking he's outwitted me?
他是故意這樣笑 讓我以為他智取我了嗎？
I'm not gonna play your games!
我可不會中你的圈套
What's this?
怎麼？
Am I on to something?
被我識破了？
You look like you've seen a ghost.
你這副樣子像見了鬼一樣
Is there a 500-yen coin in here, by any chance?
難道抽屜裡恰好有五百日元硬幣？
Gado, the answer is "true!"
卡多，答案是“真”
Maruko.
丸子
Incorrect!
答案錯誤
There's nothing.
沒有硬幣？
Nothing. No!
沒有硬幣
How can there be nothing?
怎麼會沒有硬幣？
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
You look like you've seen a ghost.
你這副樣子像見了鬼一樣
Was it an act?
你剛才是唬我的？
This guy's got some guts under this kind of pressure.
在這種壓力之下，算這傢伙有膽量
One point to Teruasa Oda!
織田照朝得一分
You did it, Teruasa.
你做到了，照朝
A weak little squirt who couldn't even follow in his parents' footsteps.
一個弱小的小鬼 連父母的腳步都跟不上
Somehow he's managed to pull it off.
竟然能設法贏一分
Certainly, the old Teruasa may have been weak.
沒錯，過去的照朝也許確實弱小
TERUASA ODA GUARDIAN OF A MINOR
（織田照朝，未成年人監護人）
STOCK TRANSFER AGREEMENT
（股份轉讓協議）
Are these the company's stocks?
這些是公司的股份嗎？
3,000 employees will soon be on the streets because of your father.
三千名員工可能很快會 因為你的父親而流落街頭
If you transfer the property and shares you inherited to us,
如果你將繼承的財產和股份 轉讓給我們
we can save them.
我們可以救他們
I'll do it.
我明白了
You will?
是嗎？
Thank you!
謝謝
His mother died early,
母親早亡
and then his father, who raised him alone, was killed.
後來獨自撫養他的父親被殺害
The comfortable world he had taken for granted
他認為理所當然的舒適世界
collapsed around him in a moment.
一瞬間在他身邊崩塌
And when the ego-driven adults turned their schemes upon Teruasa,
當卑鄙自大的成年人 把陰險手段用在照朝身上時
he did not yet understand the world,
他還沒能理解這個世界
and lost everything.
因此他失去了一切
I have a friend in India.
我在印度有個朋友
You'll be safe there.
你在那裡會很安全
So leave Seiji's case to the police.
把清司的案子交給警方吧
Take this key with you, and lay low for a while.
帶上這把鑰匙，先去避避風頭
You're sure you didn't say anything to anyone?
你沒有跟任何人透露這件事吧？
I told Ui and Yuki I'm going to study abroad in the UK.
我跟初和悠季說我要去英國留學
I know this is difficult.
我知道這很難
Please be patient.
請耐心等待時機
You were too young and powerless
你太年幼無力了
to protect what was dear to you.
保護不了親近的人
But I can't imagine what hardships you must have gone through abroad.
但我無法想像 你在國外經歷了什麼磨難
Teruasa has returned with an unbreakable spirit.
照朝這次回來，有著堅不可摧的意志
Maruko,
丸子
you can't win against me.
你是贏不了我的
A lot of nerve for someone quivering at the sight of Gado just moments ago.
剛才看到卡多還打哆嗦的人 竟然有膽子說這種話
The real game is just beginning.
真正的遊戲才剛剛開始
Take a look.
看好了
A tattoo?
刺青？
This is the real horror of ACMA:GAME.
這是ACMA:GAME遊戲真正可怕之處
Awaken
覺醒吧
the devil power!
惡魔之力
What was that?
怎麼回事？
An earthquake?
是地震嗎？
I wonder…
我真好奇
What was it?
剛剛是怎麼了
Well now…
我看看
It's minus 10 degrees.
現在溫度是負十度
What did you do?
你做了什麼？
Gado, explain to the newbie.
卡多，跟這個菜鳥解釋一下
The player who starts the game with his own key
用自己的鑰匙發起遊戲的玩家
unlocks an item he may use to his advantage.
能解鎖一個可以利用的能力 作為自己的優勢
Devil power.
這就是惡魔之力
My devil power is called "Aerial Chill,"
我的惡魔之力是“操氣冷卻”
which means I can manipulate cold air as I please.
也就是說我可以隨意操控冷空氣
Cold air?
冷空氣？
DEVIL ENCYCLOPEDIA
（《惡魔大辭典》）
Look at that! Minus 15 degrees.
看啊，降到負15度了
Getting a bit chilly!
有一點冷了呢
In a few minutes you won't be able to think straight.
幾分鐘之後，你會沒辦法冷靜思考
You'll make hasty errors of judgment,
你會倉促犯下判斷的錯誤
or think too slowly and freeze to death.
或是因為想得太慢而凍死
Get ready for some serious shivering!
準備好全身發抖吧
You call this fair?
這哪叫公平？
I said I would judge fairly.
我說的是我會公平評判
I don't remember saying the players' abilities would be fair.
我可不記得我說過玩家的能力要均等
This isn't your room anymore.
這已經不是你的房間了
It's a frozen battlefield of hell!
這是冰冷的地獄戰場
You can't beat me.
你贏不了我的
Yuki?
悠季？
Teruasa,
照朝君
concentrate on the game.
你專注玩遊戲
But what about you?
但你們怎麼辦？
You've got to win.
你一定要贏
Find the clues that lead to Seiji's killer.
獲取線索找到殺害清司的凶手
Gado, let's continue with the game.
卡多，繼續玩遊戲吧
This time the questioner is Maruko.
這一次提問者是丸子
Make your move.
出題吧
Okay, game on.
好，遊戲開始了
Ready?
我的問題是
Within a one-kilometer circular radius, with this room at its center,
以這個房間為中心 在一公里的半徑範圍內
there are more than four convenience stores.
有超過四家便利商店
True or false?
這是真還是假？
Statement accepted.
問題接受
Teruasa, you're the solver. Give your answer.
照朝，你是解題者，說出你的答案
It's strange.
奇怪
This problem seems too easy.
這個問題好像太簡單了
But…
但是…
I don't have time to think properly.
我沒有時間認真思考
Convenience stores a one-kilometer radius from here…
以這裡為中心 一公里半徑範圍內的便利商店…
First, the one round the corner…
首先角落裡有一家…
I can't remember exactly, but there are six more.
（銘木百貨）
At first glance, the answer should be, "True."
乍眼看去，答案應該為“真”
But I can't think of any other angles.
但我想不到其他角度
What's he thinking?
他在想什麼？
Does he want to make me think he's bluffing and go for "false"?
他想讓我以為他在唬我 然後回答“假”嗎？
No.
不
If that's what he wants, and it backfires, then…
如果這是他想要的 那就適得其反了，那麼…
Then, what?
該怎麼回答？
Teruasa!
照朝
What a joke, it's hardly that cold…
開什麼玩笑？根本沒冷到這種程度…
I'm just hungry.
我只是餓了
That's all?
就這樣？
It's only Mog chocolate.
我只有莫格巧克力
Thanks. That's better.
謝謝，這樣好一點了
Hurry up and answer.
快點回答吧
There are at least four convenience stores
在以這裡為中心的一公里半徑範圍內
within a one-kilometer radius of here.
至少有四家便利商店
I'm certain of it.
我對此很確定
I'm waiting…
我還在等你的回答
My answer is…
我的回答是…
"True."
“真”
Teruasa Oda,
織田照朝
you're wrong.
答案錯誤
Mitsuhide Maruko receives one point.
丸子光秀得一分
How?
怎麼可能？
Now just hold on.
等等
I thought you said you were fine with the investment.
你不是說過可以投資嗎？
It's a bit late to tell me now. The funding's already been--
現在告訴我有點晚了，融資已經…
Shit.
該死
Loot at that! Minus 20 degrees.
看啊，降到負20度了
Kani!
蟹田
Sorry.
不好意思
Teruasa Oda will offer the third statement.
由織田照朝提第三個問題
Make your move.
提問吧
It's getting colder every second.
現在每一秒都在變冷
I won't let it beat me.
我不會讓寒冷打敗我的
Okay.
好
Under this cloth…
在這塊布下面…
there is a bomb.
有一枚炸彈
True or false?
是真還是假？
A bomb?
炸彈？
You're really using the same trick?
你真的要用同一招嗎？
Statement accepted.
問題接受
The solver must answer.
解題者必須回答
He must be losing his mind in the cold.
他的腦子一定是因為低溫短路了
You can say that again.
可不是嘛
Then lemme see what's in the drawer.
那讓我看看抽屜裡有什麼
I took a peek earlier. Mind if I look again?
我之前看過一眼 介意我再看一遍嗎？
Be my guest.
隨便你看
A bomb.
炸彈
Where's the bomb?
炸彈在哪裡？
There's no bomb in here.
這裡沒有炸彈
My answer is "False"!
我的答案是“假”
But,
但是
you wouldn't use the same trick as before, would you?
你不會像剛才那樣 使用同樣的伎倆吧？
Would you look at that! Nothing.
看看，什麼也沒有
The trick is almost the same as the first one.
這一招和第一輪幾乎一模一樣
But there is one big difference.
但兩者有著巨大的區別
The answer lies under the floor,
答案埋藏在地底下
a space Maruko doesn't know about.
在丸子所不知曉的一個地方
There in an unexploded bomb from the Great War Era
在這棟大樓底下的15公尺處
buried fifteen meters under the building.
埋著一枚大戰時期的未爆炸彈
Maruko has no idea,
丸子不知道這件事
so he'll think the answer is, "False."
所以他會認為答案是“假”
My answer is, "False."
我的答案是“假”
There's no bomb.
沒有炸彈
Yes! He fell for it!
太好了，他中計了
Correct.
正確
Correct?
正確？
Mitsuhide Maruko gains a point.
丸子光秀得一分
Another win!
又贏了
I can still make it!
我還是所向無敵
He's so annoying!
他好討人厭
Gado!
卡多
National records show an unexploded bomb is buried under this building!
國家紀錄顯示 這棟大樓的地底下埋著一枚未爆炸彈
But it's not there now.
但現在底下沒有炸彈
I can assure you of that.
這一點我可以向你保證
You're telling me someone moved an unexploded bomb? How?
你是說有人挖走了一枚未爆炸彈？ 這怎麼可能？
A bomb, or an unexploded bomb?
是炸彈？還是一枚未爆炸彈？
If you don't even know that, how could you be sure of the right answer?
你如果連這個都不知道 那你是怎麼確定那是正確答案的？
What the hell?
到底怎麼回事？
What the hell is happening here?
這裡發生了什麼事？
If Maruko gets one more point, it's over.
如果丸子再得一分，遊戲就結束了
If Teruasa loses, then…
如果照朝輸了，那麼…
Fourth turn.
第四輪
The questioner is Maruko. Make your move.
提問者是丸子，提問吧
Okay, I'm gonna follow the same pattern as before.
好，我就按之前的模式來問
Here goes.
問題來了
Within a one-kilometer circular radius, with this room at the center,
以這個房間為中心 在一公里的半徑範圍內
there are at least 10,000 humans.
至少有一萬人
True or false?
這是真還是假？
At least 10,000.
至少一萬人
Statement accepted.
問題接受
The solver is Teruasa Oda. What's the answer?
解題者是織田照朝，答案是什麼？
The population of Tokyo is about 13 million.
東京的人口大約是一千三百萬
AREA: 2000 KM SQUARED
（面積：2000平方公里）
Even a rough calculation shows there must be 20,000 people.
就算是粗略計算 答案也應該是兩萬人
1 KM RADIUS - 3.14 KM SQUARED 20,000 PEOPLE
（1公里半徑 3.14平方公里，2萬人）
Even half that number is still 10,000 people.
即使減掉一半 這個範圍內依然有一萬人
But…
但是…
It's too easy again.
這還是太簡單了
Ryukan!
龍肝先生
-I'm fine. -Try and keep warm.
-我沒事 -注意保暖
Here we go! Minus 22 degrees.
降到負22度了
What are you playing at?
你在玩什麼把戲？
Here.
拿去
Use this.
用這個
-Samejima… -Yes?
-鮫島… -是
What the hell are you helping him for!
你為什麼要幫他？
Boss! We're all gonna freeze to death at this rate.
少爺，照這樣下去，我們都會凍死的
Here, Ryukan.
來，龍肝先生
Hang in there.
撐住
You're ruining the game.
你妨礙到遊戲的進行了
Now I get it.
我明白了
It's all connected.
一切都串起來了
What're you on about?
你在說什麼？
You were lying about the devil power, Aerial Chill, weren't you?
關於惡魔之力操氣冷卻的事 你撒謊了，對吧？
He was lying?
他撒謊了？
Of course, the devil power is the only explanation for the cold,
當然，惡魔之力是降溫唯一的解釋
but the drop in temperature is just a side effect.
但降溫只是一個附帶作用
That's not what the power does.
真正的惡魔之力並不是降溫
Don't talk crap with no evidence.
沒有證據就不要胡說
Evidence?
證據？
The fire alarm started, but for some reason the sprinklers didn't.
火災警報器響了 但出於某種原因，灑水器卻沒有啟動
So what?
所以呢？
I'm sure you know?
你應該知道的吧？
Fire alarms use battery power so they can keep working in a fire.
火災警報器用的是電池 所以它們在大火中仍然能運作
But sprinklers need to be connected to a water supply.
但灑水器需要連接水管
The water must have frozen.
水一定是被凍僵了
Then what about the laptop?
那電腦又該怎麼解釋？
Even though it's plugged in,
雖然它插著電源
it's using battery power.
但使用的卻是電池的電量
Gado! Can I ask a question?
卡多，我能問一個問題嗎？
I'll answer if I can.
我會盡力回答
Was this room cut off from electricity and water at the start?
這個空間從一開始 就被斷水斷電了嗎？
No.
沒有
Only human traffic and communications were blocked.
只有人員出入和通訊被阻斷
In other words,
換句話說
if you didn't cut off the power and water,
如果你沒有切斷水和電
then Maruko,
那麼丸子
I can only think of you.
我只能猜是你幹的
When you made your statements, you kept saying "this room."
當你提問的時候 你反覆提到“這個房間”
With this room at its center…
以這個房間為中心…
…a one-kilometer radius with this room at its center.
以這個房間為中心 在一公里的半徑範圍內
Perhaps the whole room was moved to a separate location?
也許整個房間被移到另一個地點了？
The whole room?
整個房間？
You misled me about what the devil power does
你利用惡魔之力誤導我
to give yourself an advantage in the game.
讓自己在遊戲中佔優勢
That's why you came up with "Aerial Chill."
所以你才編造了“操氣冷卻”這種能力
This room must have been moved somewhere with temperatures of minus 20,
這個房間一定被移到了一個 氣溫在負20度的地方
maybe to a high mountain, like Everest.
也許移到了高山上，比如聖母峰
But the bags haven't puffed up, so the air pressure can't be that low.
但包裝袋沒有膨脹 所以這裡的氣壓沒有那麼低
Then maybe somewhere flat.
那就是移到了某個平地上
Somewhere near the North Pole?
比如北極附近的某個地方？
The North Pole?
北極？
What the hell?
什麼情況？
There wouldn't be any people in a place like that…
那樣的地方人煙稀少…
so the answer is "False."
所以答案是“假”
Correct!
答案正確
Teruasa Oda wins one point.
織田照朝得一分
Two points each!
每人各得兩分
Now what?
現在如何？
What's your next move?
你的下一招是什麼？
Or are you done?
還是說你認輸？
Snake.
蛇
You're a snake.
你簡直就是一條蛇
Do you accept defeat?
你願意認輸嗎？
Don't be an idiot!
別傻了
If you're a snake,
如果你是蛇
then I'm a mongoose, a snake-eating eagle, or a weasel!
那我就是貓鼬，是吃蛇的鷹或黃鼠狼
I'm going to get more devil's keys,
我要拿到更多惡魔鑰匙
and make the family my father built even bigger and better!
讓我父親建立的家族越來越強大
Then when will your desires be satisfied?
那你的欲望要到什麼時候才能滿足？
Back when I was a kid,
我小的時候
my father showed me the devil's key for the first time,
我父親第一次讓我看惡魔鑰匙
and asked me what I wanted.
並問我想要什麼
I thought of everything I possibly could,
我開始想出所有能想到的東西
from a telescope to new cleats.
從望遠鏡到新球鞋
Then he asked me…
然後他問我…
When will your desires be satisfied?
你的欲望要到什麼時候才能滿足？
What's your point?
你想說什麼？
While I was thinking how to answer,
在我想著要怎麼回答時
my father continued.
我父親接著說
"It's desire that cannot be satisfied."
“欲壑難填”
Chasing desires in desperation only leads to bitterness.
拼命追逐欲望只會導致痛苦
The flames of desire ignite conflict.
欲望的火焰會點燃衝突
It's written in history.
這已經寫進歷史裡了
That's why, no matter how much luck you have, you shouldn't be greedy.
因此不論你有多幸運，你都不能貪婪
You mustn't obsess over getting what you want.
你不能沉迷於獲取你想要的東西
Greed is a dangerous thing.
貪婪是危險的
If you can,
如果可以的話
try to become someone who can save those
你試著成為一個拯救者吧
who become consumed by desire.
拯救被欲望吞噬的人
Honestly,
老實說
the devil's key has brought me luck.
惡魔鑰匙給我帶來了好運
But…
但是…
I've tried not to let greed swallow me.
我盡力不讓貪婪吞噬我
It's the same for you.
你也一樣
No matter how powerful your family gets,
不論你的家族變得多強大
you won't stop playing ACMA:GAME.
你都不會停止玩ACMA:GAME遊戲
The more you win, the more you'll play,
你贏得越多就越想玩
until greed consumes you, and you lose everything.
直到貪婪吞噬你，讓你失去一切
Just what the devil wants, isn't it, Gado?
這正如惡魔的意，對吧，卡多？
So, Maruko,
所以丸子
will you quit?
你會停手嗎？
It's foolish to risk your life dancing with the devil.
冒著生命危險與惡魔共舞很愚蠢
Boss…
少爺
I think it's time to move on.
是時候向前看了
Sorry to butt in,
抱歉打斷你們
but once the game starts, it isn't over until someone wins.
但是遊戲一旦開始就不會結束 直到有一方獲勝
It was you who demanded each other's lives.
是你們要求索彼此的命的
So! Let the game continue!
所以，遊戲繼續
-Wait! -Answer him.
-等等 -聽他的吧
We've got no option!
我們別無選擇
Fancy words won't help!
你再怎麼高談闊論也沒用
In the end, it's kill or be killed.
到頭來，不是殺人就是被殺
It's live or die!
不是生就是死
Now it's getting exciting.
現在遊戲變得更刺激了
The questioner is Teruasa Oda. Make your move.
提問者是織田照朝，提問吧
-Make your move!
-提問
Have it your way.
我知道了
If you're prepared to die…
如果你準備好以死接受挑戰…
I'll risk my life with all I've got.
那我會冒著生命危險全力以赴
Teruasa.
照朝君
I'm going to finish this.
我來做個了結
Here's my statement.
我的問題是
Now, the cash I own in this room
現在我在這個房間裡擁有的現金
is no more than 500 yen.
不超過五百日元
True or false?
這是真還是假？
Cash?
現金？
No more than 500 yen?
不超過五百日元？
Statement accepted.
問題接受
The solver is Maruko. Answer.
解題者是丸子，回答吧
Focus. Focus.
專注，要保持專注
He's the type to know exactly how much money he has in this room.
他知道自己在這個房間裡有多少現金
Wait.
等等
He said no more than 500 yen.
他說不超過五百日元
Got it!
找到了
The 500-yen coin he used in the first game.
這是他在第一輪遊戲裡 用的五百日元硬幣
I forgot that I put it in my pocket.
我忘了我把它放進了自己的口袋裡
So,
所以
that's the reason he said "no more than 500 yen."
這就是他說“不超過五百日元”的原因
Another trap.
又是一個陷阱
But I spotted it just in time.
還好我及時發現了
The answer is "True."
答案是“真”
I'm the winner.
我是贏家
But, wait.
但是，等等
Wait, wait.
等等…
I need to slow down.
我得慢下來
Up until the fourth statement,
在提出第四個問題之前
I would have answered "True" without a second guess.
我肯定想也不想就回答“真”
This asshole has set me up before.
但這個混蛋剛才擺了我一道
This could be a trap too!
這或許也是圈套
"No more than 500 yen" means it could be exactly 500 yen.
“不超過五百日元” 表示它可以等於五百日元
But whether I noticed that or not, the answer would be "True."
但不論我注意到與否，答案都是“真”
But knowing this lowlife scumbag,
但是以我對這個廢柴人渣的瞭解
there must be more to it.
事情絕對沒有這麼簡單
Then I've got to top him somehow.
那我就得想辦法超越他
I'll go for the opposite of what I think!
我要給出和自己的想法相反的答案
No, wait.
不，等等
Calm down.
冷靜
I need to check again.
我需要再檢查一遍
That's it!
對了
I just got shivers down my spine.
我都興奮到顫抖起來了
Yes,
沒錯
the only Japanese coin that withstands fire is the 500-yen coin.
五百日元硬幣是唯一耐火的日本硬幣
Got you!
找到你了
Certain proof.
確鑿的證據
My route to victory!
讓我走向勝利的路標
Boss!
少爺
I've made it. I've finally made it!
我成功了，我終於成功了
I've outsmarted your filthy trap!
我識破了你骯髒的圈套
The 500 yen left from the fire,
在火中剩下的五百日元硬幣
and the 500 yen we used in the first game.
和我們在第一輪遊戲中 使用的五百日元硬幣
No matter how you interpret it, there's 1000 yen in this room!
不論你怎麼解釋 這個房間裡都有一千日元
Definitely!
無可爭辯
Listen up!
聽好了
The answer is "False"!
答案是“假”
HEISEI YEAR 23 - HEISEI YEAR 24
（平成23年，平成24年）
Gado, is it right? Tell me!
卡多，答對了嗎？快告訴我
Mitsuhide Maruko.
丸子光秀
Incorrect!
答案錯誤
One point to Teruasa Oda.
織田照朝得一分
There are two 500-yen coins.
這裡有兩個五百日元硬幣
See for yourself!
你自己看看
It's incorrect.
答案錯誤
Maruko,
丸子
it's you who should look more carefully.
該好好看的人是你
They're different.
不一樣
Is it counterfeit?
這是假幣？
I got it from my father as a birthday present.
這是我父親給我的生日禮物
Happy Birthday, Teruasa.
生日快樂，照朝
Just this?
就這個？
The 500 yen he gave me
他給我的五百日元硬幣
was actually a GPS tracker, to keep me safe.
其實是一個保障我安全的 全球定位追蹤器
GPS?
全球定位？
The battery is dead and it doesn't work anymore…
電池已經耗盡，它也無法運作了…
but for some reason, I kept it with me.
但出於某種原因，我還留著它
Your dad was the one who helped you at the very end.
你的父親在最後幫助了你
Is that allowed?
可以這樣嗎？
Gado is the judge.
卡多是裁判
If you don't like it, ask him.
如果你不認可，可以問他
The winner of the game, "True or False,"
“真偽心眼”遊戲的贏家
is Teruasa Oda.
是織田照朝
Teruasa Oda, victory is yours.
織田照朝，你贏了
Mitsuhide Maruko's key is yours.
丸子光秀的鑰匙歸你了
So let's settle up.
我們來清算賭注吧
As requested by Teruasa Oda,
根據織田照朝的要求
after sharing what he knows about the devil's keys,
在分享關於惡魔鑰匙的已知訊息後
Maruko will lose his life.
丸子將會失去生命
Wait. Wait!
等等
There is no argument!
這無可爭辯
Well, well, this certainly kept me entertained.
今天這場遊戲還真精彩
With that, the game "True of False" comes to an end--
那樣的話 “真偽心眼”遊戲就此結束…
It's not over yet.
還沒結束
What?
什麼？
Like I said at the start.
我在開始時說過
I demand the right to take Maruko's life at any moment.
我要隨時都可以奪走丸子性命的權利
So,
所以
I'll take his life in 200 years.
我要在兩百年以後再取他的性命
200 years?
兩百年？
Okay with you, Maruko?
你同意嗎，丸子？
What?
什麼？
You're an interesting guy.
你這個傢伙真有意思
But debts must always be paid.
但欠的債總是要還的
What are you saying?
你想說什麼？
This is the end of the game!
遊戲結束
Teruasa! Yuki!
照朝，悠季
Ui!
初君
Earlier, this place had completely disappeared.
剛才這個地方完全消失了
Then it suddenly came back.
然後它又突然間回來了
What's going on, Teruasa?
這是怎麼回事，照朝？
Thank you.
謝謝
You saved my life.
你救了我一命
Maruko,
丸子
where did you get the key?
你是從哪裡得到鑰匙的？
About two weeks ago, it just fell from the heavens.
大約兩週之前，它直接從天上掉下來
Riichi.
立直
-Perfect! -What?
-太好了 -什麼？
Riichi! Three concealed triplets in one go.
立直，三暗刻
One dora. Mangan!
一個寶牌，滿貫
Ron! Baiman, 24,000 points!
榮和，倍滿，兩萬四千點
Shit!
該死的
At first I thought someone was pranking me.
一開始我以為有人在捉弄我
What the hell?
這是什麼鬼？
Wait for it… Tsumo!
就等它了，自摸
Four completely concealed triplets. Rinshankaiho!
四暗刻，嶺上開花
Tsumo.
自摸
Nine Gates.
九蓮寶燈
No way…
不會吧
I hit the jackpot while gambling,
我在賭博中贏了大獎
and shared a drink with a rival family to mend broken bonds.
跟敵對家族一起喝酒 修復了破裂的關係
Simply put, luck came my way.
簡單來說，好運總是站在我這邊
I was blinded by greed, and lost sight of myself.
貪婪讓我變得盲目並失去自我
Then one day…
後來有一天
UNKNOWN CALLER
（未知來電）
…I got a phone call.
我接到了一通電話
Who's this?
你是誰？
That key is known as the devil's key.
那把鑰匙叫做惡魔鑰匙
It's the key to your dreams that makes anything you desire come true.
這是實現夢想的鑰匙 可以讓你夢想成真
Who was it?
那個人是誰？
I don't know.
我不知道
Boss.
少爺
UNKNOWN CALLER
（未知來電）
Maruko,
丸子
you got your hands on a devil's key, huh?
你獲得了一把惡魔鑰匙，對吧？
Where is the key?
鑰匙在哪裡？
I know that voice.
我認得那個聲音
Could that be Teruasa Oda?
那是織田照朝嗎？
Looks like you won then?
這麼說你贏了？
Where are you?
你在哪裡？
Don't get overexcited.
別那麼激動
You know about the 99 keys, don't you?
你知道99把鑰匙的事吧？
So what?
那又怎麼樣？
Just like Maruko,
像丸子一樣
there will be others chosen by the key
這裡會有其他人被鑰匙選中
who will cross your path.
然後跟你對上
That hurt.
好痛啊
Welcome to the store, can I help you?
歡迎光臨，有什麼可以為您服務的？
If you want to meet me,
你如果想要見我
battle them in the game.
就在遊戲中打敗他們
Beat them and win the keys.
打敗他們，然後贏得鑰匙
If you do that, we can meet.
如果你做得到，我們就能見面
What a load of bullshit!
胡說八道
I will find you, and make you pay for killing my father.
我會找到你的 讓你為殺害我父親付出代價
A debt to be paid…
欠的債總是要還的…
Yes,
好啊
I'm looking forward to it.
我會等你的
One more thing.
還有一件事
The debts of ACMA:GAME
ACMA:GAME遊戲的債
must always be paid.
總是要還的
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
Mitsuhide's gone.
光秀不見了
He was here just a moment ago.
他剛剛還在這裡
Where'd he go?
他去哪裡了？
Look! He dropped the key.
看，他的鑰匙掉了
This is the key he took from Honda.
這是他從本多那裡奪走的鑰匙
He left the key and disappeared.
他留下鑰匙後消失了
Did the devil kill him?
是惡魔殺了他嗎？
But Teruasa postponed his death for 200 years.
但照朝說要將他的死期延後兩百年
Hey, kid!
小鬼
Is this the debt?
這就是債嗎？
Kid, where are you? Mitsuhide!
小鬼，你在哪裡？光秀
But why?
但怎麼會這樣？
NEXT EPISODE
（下集預告）
-Screw you! -I want these people eliminated.
-去你的 -我要把這些人除掉
All three of us will be destroyed by the devil.
我們三個都會被惡魔給毀了
This game is called "Shadow Step."
這個遊戲叫“映影頭踏”
Teruasa, I can see your shadow. Go!
照朝，我看得到你的影子，快走
This is your graveyard.
這是你的墳墓
Teruasa!
照朝